In this video, we will look at how to
enter an accounts receivable invoice and
credit memo in Dynamics SL and compare
that process to the experience for
entering these entries in Dynamics 365
Business Central.
In the SL system, navigate to the
accounts receivable module and then
invoice and memo.
In invoice and memo, I'll begin by
entering an invoice for our customer
Trey Research.
Once I enter the customer's ID, I can
enter the details of the invoice.
Once everything is entered, save and
release the batch.
In our example, let's say a credit memo
now needs to be applied to the invoice
we just entered.
In the same invoice and memo screen,
change the document type to credit memo.
Select Trey Research
and then enter $90 credit.
Save and release the batch.
Now that we have an invoice and a credit
memo, we need to apply the credit memo
to the earlier invoice.
From the accounts receivable module
menu, select payment application.
In payment application, select customer
Trey Research and then change the type
to equal credit memo.
In the number field, select the credit
memo entered earlier.
Notice in the grid the outstanding
invoice from earlier is available.
In the grid, select the invoice line and
enter the $90 amount to be applied.
Populate the payment application batch,
save and release.
Now let's look at how we can enter an
invoice and credit memo in Dynamics 365
Central.
There are a couple different ways to
enter a customer invoice in Business
Central. You can navigate to the sales
journal from the role center, search for
sales journals, then in sales journals,
you can enter multiple entries for
multiple customers.
For our example, we will enter a single
customer invoice using the sales invoice
screen.
Navigate to sales invoice. From the role
center, select sales from the top menu
and then sales invoice.
In sales invoice, select new from the
action menu bar.
In sales invoice, select customer name
Trey Research.
In the grid area, enter a line. Notice
you can enter an invoice line for
several options allowing you to invoice
for items and services in a single
invoice.
In this example, I will select item.
In the number field, select an item from
the drop-down list and populate the
remaining fields to complete the
invoice.
From the top action menu, select post
and then preview posting.
If you want to verify the posting
entries prior to the posting process.
Now, post the invoice.
A credit memo can also be entered and
applied to entries in sales journal
by selecting the credit memo line type.
But in our example, we will enter a
credit memo in sales credit memo.
From the role center
action menu, select sales and then sales
credit memo.
In the sales credit memo list, select
new. In sales credit memo screen, select
our customer, Trey Research.
In the general fast tab, select show
more. You can see the fields available
to select the applies to doc type and
applies to doc number.
This allows you to enter and apply the
credit memo in one entry.
Go to lines.
Keep the type equal item.
Set the number to the item we selected
in the invoice earlier
and in amount of $90.
From the action menu, select post.
Preview posting to verify the entries
are being applied to the selected
invoice.
Now, post the invoice.
To learn more about Business Central,
see the following resources.